Guide to the Ralph I. Gifford Photographs circa 1910s - 1947
Oregon State University Libraries, University Archives
- Numbered Series, circa 1935 - 1947; Series IV; 675 prints, 496 film negatives, 5 nitrate negatives, and 4 glass negatives
  - "Days End," taken at Crown Point, Columbia R. Highway at sunset, November 6, 1940; 0614; 5 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
    Postcard (PC) #157; 4x5 SG camera; C. Ziess lens; 1/25 exposure; F22 stop; G filter; SPP film; developed in 60-a; Kodabrom paper; developed in EK 72
  - "Spring Fever" fishing on the Chetco River, southern Oregon coast, 0615
    8x10 East. View camera; 7 1/2" Protar lens; 1/25 at F32; SPP film; developed in 60A; Velox paper; developed in EK 72
    - 5 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
    - 8 prints (Box 2)
    - 3 prints, including 1 hand-colored (Box 73, 74)
      Hand-colored print on exhibit.
    - 3 prints (Box *)
  - "Cargo" American ship loading lumber, Port Astoria, Astoria, Oregon, 0616
    4x5 SG camera; C. Ziess lens; 1/50 at F22; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabrom F#3 paper; developed in EK 72
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 3 prints (Box 2, 73)
  - "Pastoral" Mt. Hood and dairy herd in clover near Dufur, Oregon, 0617
    4x5 Speed Graphic, 1/50 sec. at F22; G. filter; F8 12 counts overall; Kodabowide F2 B extra on foreground then give mountail a little more
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 3 prints (Box 2, 73)
  - "Pastoral" Mt. Hood and dairy herd in clover near Dufur, Oregon, 0618; print and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
    4x5 Speed Graphic, 1/50 at F22; G. Filter
  - Indians netting salmon at Celilo Falls near The Dalles, 0619
    4x5 Speed Graphic, 1/200 at F16; Superpan Press film; print numbered 202.
    - 4x5 negative and 5x7 copy negative (Box 8, 61)
    - 2 prints (Box 2)
  - Mt. Hood at apple blossom time, upper Hood River Valley, 0620
    4x5 Speed Graphic, 1/50 at F16; Superpan Press film; 6 counts foreground on up to 10 counts mountian F8 stop; Sepia G#3=8x10 vertical 30 sec and 10 sec on mountain; new soup 5 counts straight 1 extra mountain
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 14 prints (Box 2, 73)
  - Sunset on the Willamette River, Salem, 0621; 4x5 negative and hand-colored print (Box 8, 73)
    4x5 Speed Graphic; 1/100 at F22; G. filter; Superpan Press film; one #5 flash bulb in fire and one on camera
  - Cuthroat Trout from Chetco River, southern Oregon, 0622; 2 prints and 5x7 negative (Box 2, 61)
    5x7 Eastman View, 1/25 at F22; Superpan Press film; cloudy
  - Timberline Lodge and Mt. Hood, Oregon, 0623
    5x7 Eastman View; 1/50 at F22; G. filter; Superpan Press film; made from top of 70 ft. tree; 4 counts F11 F2 paper
    - 5x7 negative (Box 61)
    - 2 prints (Box 2, 74)
  - Mt. Hood from Lost Lake, Oregon, 0624; 7 8x10 prints and 5x7 glass negative (Box 2, 36)
    Postcard (PC) #167; G3 F11 4 sec.; F3 paper 7H stop 6 counts; black and white with border
  - Hereford cattle on way to summer pasture from Medford, Oregon, 0625
    5x7 Eastman View; 1/50 at F22; Superpan Press film; owned by Comm. Ben Day
    - 5x7 negative (Box 61)
    - 5 prints (Box 2, 74)
  - Pounding surf, Brookings, Oregon, 0626; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    4x5 Speed Graphic, 1/100 at F16; G. filter; Superpan Press film
  - Pounding surf, Brookings, Oregon (Box 2)
    Similar to 0626.
  - Fishing boats entering Depoe Bay, Oregon, 0627; print and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
  - Trailing sheep near Meacham, Oregon, 0628; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
  - Spouting Horn, Depoe Bay, Oregon, October 22, 1941; 0629; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    4x5 SG camera; 4.5-K.A. lens; 1/200 at F12; G filter; SPP film; developed in K.K. 60A; F. Kodabrom paper; developed in EK #72
  - Pounding surf, Depoe Bay, Oregon, October 22, 1941; 0631; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    4x5 K.A.; 1/200 at F12; G. filter; SPP film; developed in 60 A; F. Kodabrom paper; developed in EK 72
  - Vista House, Crown Point, Columbia River Highway; made between showers, October 12, 1940; 0632; 15 prints and 2 4x5 negatives (Box 2, 8)
    Postcard (PC) #156; 4x5 SG camera; C. Ziess lens; 1/50 at F16; G. filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabrom F3 paper; developed in EK 72.
  - Snow Geyser, near North Powder, Oregon; rotery plow in action, 0633; print (Box 2)
    Six views; print of view A; views A, B, C, D, and E are 4x5 negatives; view F is a 5x7 negative. 4x5 SG camera; C. Ziess lens; 1/200 at F22; K2 filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabrom F3 paper; developed in EK 72
    - 5 4x5 negatives and 5x7 negative (Box 8, 61)
    - print (Box 2)
  - Snow Geyser, near North Powder, Oregon; close up of geyser from plow dirctly into sun, 0634; print and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
    4x5 SG camera; C. Ziess lens; 1/200 at F26; K2 filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabrom F3 paper; developed in EK 72
  - The Mower; horse drawn, Tualatin, Oregon, 0635
    4x5 SG camera; 4.5 K.A. lens; 1/200 at F16; G. filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabrom paper; developed in EK 72
    - 3 prints (Box 2, 74)
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Summer afternoon, Chetco River, Southern Oregon coast, 0636; 8x10 negative (Box 69)
    Vertical; 8x10 East View camera; Vesito soft focus lens; 1/25 at F22; Pan Press film; developed in 60A; Velox paper; developed in EK 72
  - Western Sunset, Southern Oregon coast near Brookings, Oregon, 0637; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
    8x10 East View camera; 7 1/2 Proter lens; 1/100 at F22; SPP film; developed in 60A; F Kodabrom paper; developed in EK 72
  - Western sunset; Southern Oregon coast near Brookings, Oregon, 0638
    8x10 East View camera; 7 1/2 Proter lens; 1/100 at F22; SPP film; developed in 60A; Velox paper; developed in EK 72
    - 8x10 negative (Box 69)
    - 2 prints (Box 2, *)
  - Lone Sentinel tree at Crater Lake National Park, Oregon, June 21, 1940; 0639
    Postcard (PC) #158; 5x7 East View camera; 5 1/4" Ziess; 1/50 at F22; G filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabrom paper; developed in EK 72.
    - 15 prints (Box 2, 73)
    - 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - Spindrift, Oregon coast, near Yachats, 0640; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    4x5 SG camera; C. Ziess lens; 1/100 at F16; G filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabrom paper; developed in EK 72
  - Sheep on way to summer pasture, near Pilot Rock, Oregon, 0641; 3 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
    4x5 SG camera; C. Ziess lens; 1/100 at F22; K2 filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabrom paper; developed in EK 72
  - Sheep on way to bedding grounds; meadows near Mt. Hood, Oregon, 0642
    5x7 F. View; C. Ziess lens; exposure 1/200 at F11; Pan Press film; developed in 60A; Kodabrom paper; developed in EK 72; 2 1/2 to 3 counts, F3 paper, F11 stop
    - 5x7 nitrate negative (Box 60)
    - 5 prints (Box 2)
    - 2 oversize mounted prints (Box 74)
  - Crab fisherman, Cannon Beach, Oregon; bear cub on beach smashes crab with paw and proceeds to make meal of him, 0644-0645; 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
    4x5 SG camera; KA lens; 1/200 at F22; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabrom paper; developed in EK 72; one of the images available online.
  - Rugged coast near Brookings, Oregon, 0646; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    4x5 SG camera; C. Ziess lens; 1/50 at F22; G filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabrom paper; developed in EK 72
  - Rhododendrons on Mt. Hood, 0647; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    4x5 SG camera; KA lens; 1/10 at F22; A filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabrom paper; developed in EK 72
  - "Warning, Danger" train at railroad crossing (reckless driver could be superimposed on front of engine), 0648; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    4x5 SG camera; KA lens; 1/200 at F22; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabrom paper; developed in EK 72
  - Train engineer, 2 prints (Box 2)
  - Glass float, near Brookings, Oregon; Japanese glass fish net float covered with mussels, 0649-0650; print for 0650 and 4x5 negatives (Box 2, 8)
    4x5 SG camera; C Ziess lens; 1/100 at F22; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabrom paper; developed in EK 72
    - 0649, 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 0650, print and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
  - Ranch scene near Dufur, Oregon, 0651; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
    4x5 SG camera; KA lens; 1/25 at F22; A filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabrom paper; developed in EK 72; 3 1/2 counts, F8 stop, F2 paper
  - Storm waves, Boiler Bay, Oregon, October 22, 1941; 0652-0653; 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
    4x5 SG camera; KA lens; 1/200 at F11; G filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabrom paper; developed in EK 72
  - Serration, Short Hand Beach, Oregon (serrated sand), October 22, 1941; 0654; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    4x5 SG camera; KA lens; 1/100 at F22; G filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabrom paper; developed in EK 72
  - Mt. Hood, 0655; 4 prints and 5x7 glass negative (Box 2, 36)
    On the headwaters of the Sandy river on western slope of Mt. Hood; reproduction is slowly covering the scars of a forest fire which probably raged a half century ago, the result of some carelessly thrown match or unguarded campfire. In recent years the Mt. Hood area has been reasonably free of devastating flames. Mt. Hood, 11,245 feet high, was named in 1792 in honor of Viscount Hood of the English peerage. Oregon State Highway Commision photo by Gifford; 5x7 E. View; Ziess Proter; G filter
  - Mt. Hood, Buzzard Point on Mt. Hood Loop; old Oregon trail passes just beyond this point, September 9, 1940; 0656; 3 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
    4x5 SG camera; EK lens; 1/25 at F16; G filter; SPP film; developed in DK LO; Kodabromide paper; developed in EK 72
  - Mt. Hood, Upper Hood River Valley, 0657; 3 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
    4x5 SG camera; KA lens; 1/25 at F22; G filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabromide paper; developed in EK 72
  - Mt. Hood and rhododendrons, on Laurel Hill, Mt. Hood Loop, 0658; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
    4x5 SG camera; EK lens; 1/25 at F22; G filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabromide paper; developed in EK 72
  - Mt. Hood, Hood River meadows on Mt. Hood Loop, 0659; 5 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
  - Mt. Hood and Timberline Lodge from tree, 0660; 7 prints and 5x7 negative (Box 2, 61)
  - Mt. Hood and squaw grass from Wapanita Highway cut off, 0661
    5x7 EV; Ziess Proter; 1/25 at F22; G.1 filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabromide paper; developed in EK 72; 16 counts foreground 6 more counts for mountain
    - 4x5 negative and 5x7 negative (Box 8, 61)
    - 3 prints (Box 2)
  - Squaws on Parade, Pendleton Round Up, Pendleton, Oregon, 0662; print and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
    4x5 SG camera; KA lens; 1/200 at F22; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabromide paper; developed in EK 72
  - Pendleton Round Up, teepee village, 0663; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    4x5 SG camera; KA lens; 1/200 at F16; G filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabromide paper; developed in EK 72
  - Crooked R. Canyon near Cove, Oregon, 0664; print and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
    4x5 SG camera; KA lens; 1/100 at F16; G filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabromide paper; developed in EK 72
  - Boiler Bay, Oregon, 0665; 4 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
    4x5 SG camera; KA lens; 1/200 at F22; K2 filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabromide paper; developed in EK 72; F11 #3, 6 sec. shade below horizion burn in wave 1 sec.
  - Oregon Coast near Brookings; Charlotte Lytle, Marshfield, Oregon, 0666; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    KA lens; 1/200 at F16; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabromide paper; developed in EK 72
  - Sunset at Harris State Park, Brookings, Oregon, 0667; 2 prints and 5x7 negative (Box 2, 61)
    5x7 E. View; (?) lens; 1/100 at F16; K filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabromide paper; developed in EK 72
  - Split Rail Fence, Eastern Oregon, 0668; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    4x5 SG camera; KA lens; 1/100 at F22; G filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabromide paper; developed in EK 72
  - Spouting Horn at Cape Perpetua, 0669; print and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
  - Fossil Beds on the John Day River near Mitchell Point, 0670; 3 prints and 5x7 negative (Box 2, 61)
    5x7 EV camera; Goerz lens; 1/25 at F22; K3 filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabromide paper; developed in EK 72; 5 counts F8 no. 2 paper
  - South toward Cannon Beach from Ecola Park, 0671; 8x10 negative (Box 69)
    8x10 EV camera; (?) lens; 1/50 at F22; K3 filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabromide paper; developed in EK 72
  - Blue Lake and Mt. Washington on Santiam Highway in Cascade Mountains, 0672; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
    4x5 SG camera; KA lens; 1/50 at F22; G filter; SPP film; developed in 60A; Kodabromide paper; developed in EK 72
  - Gulls at Cape Kiawanda, 0673; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Foxgloves and poppies on Southern Oregon coast, 0674; 3 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
    Graphic view; K2 filter; Super pan press film; 1/50 at F16
  - North Falls, Silver Creek Falls State Park, 0675; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Breaking waves, Boiler Bay, Oregon, 0676
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 2 prints (Box 2, 73)
  - Sea gulls on parade, 0677; print and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
  - Over the top; jumping a snow cornice on Mt. Hood, 0678; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Mt. Hood from Laurel Hill, 0679; print and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
  - "The Harvest" Mt. Hood and oat sheaves, Upper Hood River Valley, 0680
    F8 6 counts; F2 Kodabrom
    - 5x7 negative (Box 61)
    - 2 prints (Box 2)
    - 3 oversize mounted prints (Box 73, 74)
  - Ralph Gifford logo, 0681; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Two sail boats on Elk lake, 0682; print and 8x10 negative (Box 2, 69)
  - Two sail boats on Elk Lake (Box 2)
    Vertical view.
  - Elk Lake, 2 prints (Box 2)
    View of Mount Bachelor and Broken Top; lake reached by forest road; resort for fishermen and tourists.
  - Timberline Lodge at Mt. Hood covered in snow; taken from a tree, 0684; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Woman sitting on edge of Crooked River Gorge, 0685; print and 4x5 negatives (Box 2, 8)
  - Woman sitting and looking at Wizard Island, Crater Lake, Oregon, 0686; 2 prints and 5x7 negative (Box 2, 61)
    Kodabromide F3 6 counts
  - Rogue River near its source, 0687; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - Behold the fisherman, 0688; 2.5x5 negative of text (Box 8)
  - Mt. Hood and oat sheaves in foreground, 0689; print and 5x7 negative (Box 2, 61)
  - Rustic bridge in Silver Creek Falls Park, 0690
    G-#3 8 sec. dodging corner; 4 sec. ea side top-10 sec sky, F11
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 6 prints (Box 2)
    - oversize print and art print engraving (Box 73, 74)
  - Blossom time, Salem, Oregon, April 1939; 0691
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 26 prints (Box 2)
    - 4 oversize prints and 1 oversize mounted print (Box 73, 74)
  - Gifford Logos, 0693; 4x5 negative and 5x7 negative (Box 8, 61)
  - The Balers, 0694; 3 4x5 negatives and 2 oversize prints (Box 8, 73)
    5 counts at F8 on Kromide 2; 3 counts more shading bale and more on left
  - Oregon in Miniature Sets, 0695
    View sets of small prints (approximately 2 x 3 inches) that were sold at souvenir shops throughout the state. Original camera negatives of most of the images are described separately in this series or elsewhere in the collection.
    - Miscellaneous Views, Set #1 (Box 2)
      Views depict the State Capitol in Salem, Oregon; fruit tree blossoms near Salem; a rustic bridge at Silver Creek, Oregon; Crater Lake; sunset on the Willamette River; Vista House on the Columbia River; a western sunset on the Oregon coast; and Timberline Lodge at Mt. Hood, Oregon. Includes a set in envelope, uncut 8x10 sheets of miniature views, 8x10 prints of each view, and assembled master copy negative.
    - Mt. Hood, Oregon, Set #2 (Box 2)
      Views show Timberline Lodge; apple blossom time; Mt. Hood from the Little Sandy River and Laurel Hill; harvest time in the Hood River Valley; a winter sunset; rhododendrons; and squaw grass on the Wapanita Highway. Includes a set in envelope, 8x10 prints of each view, and assembled master copy negative.
    - Silver Creek Falls State Park, Set #3 (Box 2)
      Views of several waterfalls in the park and a rustic bridge over the North Fork of Silver Creek. Includes a set in envelope, uncut 8x10 sheets of miniature views, 8x10 prints of each view, and assembled master copy negative.
    - Salem Views, Set #4
      Views depict the Administration Building at Willamette University; Post Office; Forestry Building; moat at the Oregon State Penitentiary; Liberty Street in downtown Salem; State Library; State Capitol; and Marion County Courthouse with rhododendrons in the foreground. Includes only the assembled master copy negative and negatives for captions.
      - assembled master copy negative (Box 2)
      - 4x5 negative and 5x7 negative (Box 8, 61)
    - Advertisement for Oregon in Miniature Sets, 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - Mt. Hood, Oregon, in summer garb; taken from Timberline Road, 0696; print and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 61)
    Not released.
  - Heceta Head lighthouse on Oregon coast, 0697; 8x10 negative (Box 69)
  - Oregon State Capital building, 0698; print and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 61)
    Horizontal view.
  - Oregon State Capital building, 0699; print and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 61)
  - Evening dip at Harris State Park; girl with feet in surf, 0700; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Rainbow beach near Brookings, Oregon, 0701; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Crooked River Bridge, 0702
    - 4x5 negative and 5x7 copy negative (Box 8, 61)
    - 2 prints (Box 3)
  - Woman standing next to large tree, Metolious River, 0703; 4x5 negative and print (Box 8, 73)
  - Avenue of pine lumber, Klamath Falls, Oregon, 0704; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
    See also color transparency.
  - Man fly fishing in Alsea River, 0705-0706
    - 0705, print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    - 0706, 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Rogue River near Union, 0707; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - Rogue River mail boat, 0708; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Rogue river mail boat, 2 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Winter at Iufers Nursery, Salem, Oregon, 0709-0710
    - 0709, 4x5 negative and print (Box 8, 73)
      Print is affixed on back of mount for 0952.
    - 0710, 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - The water hole; sheep on range near Mitchell, 0711; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Oregon State Capital building; long shot from side, 0712; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Oregon State Capital building covered in snow, 0713
    - 5x7 negative (Box 61)
    - 4 prints (Box 3, 73)
  - Oregon State Capital building covered in snow (vertical), 0714; print and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 61)
  - The Circuit Rider statue in front of Oregon State Capital building covered in snow, 0715; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - Azalea Park observatory, Brookings, Oregon, 0716; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Sahalie Falls, McKenzie River, 0717; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Man fly fishing at base of Tamolitsh Falls, McKenzie River, 0718; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Docked fishing boats at sunset, Astoria, Oregon, 0719; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Native American woman on horseback at Pendleton Round Up, 0720; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Night Rider; cowboy on night patrol, 0721; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Mt. Hood; mountain harvest, shocked oat field, 0722; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
    See also color transparencies.
  - Indian in middle of tepees, 0723; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Azalea Park observatory, Brookings, Oregon, 0724; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Close up of azalea (rhododendron?) blossom, 0725; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Oregon City paper mills and Mt. St. Helens, 0726; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Drifting snow on an Eastern Oregon highway, 0727; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Tumalo Falls from river at base, near Bend, Oregon, 0728; print and 2 5x7 negatives (Box 3, 61)
  - Fisherman sleeping on shore dreaming of fish, 0729; 5x7 copy negative and oversize print (Box 61, 74)
  - Camp scene Elk Lake, 1940; 0730; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    no. 2 paper; 7 counts
  - Sailboating on Elk Lake, Cascade Mountains, Oregon, 0731; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    F3 paper; 4 1/2 counts; fresh developer
  - Sailboating on Elk Lake, 0732; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Marshmallow roast on Elk Lake, Oregon, 0733; 3 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    This lake is in the Eastern part of the state and is a great haunt for the fisherman. It lies a little south west of Bend, Oregon and is reached by highway called Century Drive out of Bend. F3 paper; 5 counts.
  - Mt. Batchelor from Sparks Meadows; 2 women walking, 0734; 3 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Girl holding Japanese glass net float with mussels on top of it, 0735
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 2 prints (Box 3, 73)
  - The Barrier; man fishing at base of Tumalo Falls, 0736; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Whale Rock and Ben G., Curry Co., Oregon, 0737; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Natural bridge and Smugglers Cove, Curry Co. coast, 0738; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Smugglers cove from beach showing entrance; water running through hole in rock in background, 0739; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Natural Arch, Curry Co. coast, 0740; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Harris State Park from hill, 0741; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Sundown, Harris State Park, Brookings, Oregon, 0742; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - Azalea Queen, Marie Hassett, Brookings, Oregon, 0743; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - Salmon fishing, mouth of Rogue River, Gold Beach, Oregon, 0744; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Fishing Rocks, Boiler Bay, Oregon, 0745; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Sheep at Deschutes River bridge, 0746; 4 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Mt. Hood from Timberline Road in summer, 0747; 2 prints and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 61)
  - Canadian geese on pond or lake, 0748; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Man hunting ducks on Dee Lake, 0749; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Rotary Snow plow cleaning early snow on Mt. Hood Loop Highway below government camp, Oregon., 0750; 3 prints and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 61)
    This road is kept open all winter for the pleasure of hundreds of skiers from Portland, Oregon besides the trucks that use the road on their run to Eastern Oregon.
  - Three Finger Jack from north Santiam Highway in winter, 0751; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - McKenzie Highway, 0752; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Jumping snow cornice on Mt. Hood, 0753; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Lava cast tree mold, Bend, Oregon, 0754; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    See also image A-503
  - Five pines on Metolius River, 0755; 2 prints and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 61)
    3 counts give more to foreground; no 2 paper F8 also limbs in upper right
  - Evening shadows on Elk Lake, 0756; 8x10 negative (Box 69)
  - Afterglow, sunset on Mt. Hood, 0757; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - Sport fishing at sunset, Columbia River at Astoria, 0758; 4x5 negative and oversize print (Box 8, 73)
  - Storm clouds and Phantom Ship, Crater Lake, Oregon, 0759; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Mast of Phantom Ship and Wizard Island, Crater Lake, Oregon, 0760; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    30 counts at F11
  - Two girls at base of falls on Oregon coast, Curry Co., 0761; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Boat tied to shore of Diamond Lake, 0762; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Mural in Oregon House of Representatives titled Champoeg, 1943; 0763; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Klamath Lake and Mt. McLoughlin, 0764-0765; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Evening shadows, Mt. Hood, 0766; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - Evening shadows, Mt. Hood (telephoto), 0767; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - The Circuit Rider, statue in front of Oregon State Capital building, 0768; print and 2 4x5 negatives (Box 3, 8)
  - Salem Post Office and rhododendrons, 0769; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Marion County Courthouse and rhododendrons, 0770
    Postcard (PC) #184; 3 or 4 counts; F8 2 paper
    - 4x5 negative and 5x7 negative (Box 8, 61)
    - 4 prints (Box 3)
  - State Forestry Building, Salem, 0771; print and 2 4x5 negatives (Box 3, 8)
  - The Moat, State Penitentiary; horizontal views, 0772; print and 2 4x5 negatives (Box 3, 8)